Rachel Meadows

Full-Stack Software Developer

Contact Details



021 02278121



rachelmeadowsdev@gmail.com



Summary

Kia ora! I'm a full-stack software developer and recent graduate of Enspiral Dev Academy. Before transitioning into software, I spent 3 years in a fast-paced SaaS startup, where my responsibilities spanned management, business analysis, and product development.

Outside of work, I like building projects that relate to text processing and generation (mostly in Python). I'm also a volunteer sportsfighting coach and enjoy collaborative tabletop games.

Experience

Jan 2022 - Apprentice Software Developer

May 2022 Enspiral Dev Academy

- Enspiral Dev Academy is an intensive, 15-week full-stack bootcamp that emulates a best-practice commercial environment.
- Technologies and skills I learned in this course include:
 - JavaScript (ES6).
 - · React and Redux.
 - Server-side development (Node.js, Express.js) and templating (Handlebars.js).
 - SQL database design and development (using SQLite3 and Knex.js).
 - HTML5 & CSS3.
 - REST and API architectures (invoking API routes with Insomnia, consuming APIs with Superagent, testing API calls with Supertest).
 - Test-driven development (Jest and React Testing Library), distributed version control (Git and GitHub), pair programming, and Agile methodologies.
 - Teamwork, giving and receiving feedback, and communication techniques.
- Our final project, SERV., allows customers to post jobs to a board that service businesses can make quotes on. Myself and 4 other students built this in 6 days, using React, Redux, Bootstrap, AuthO, and SQLite / Knex.js. As our team's backend lead, I was responsible for the API, routes, database functions, and some of the business logic. You can view the site live at https://www.heroku.com/serv.

Nov 2018 – Operations Manager (July 2020 – November 2021)
Nov 2021 Research Analyst (November 2018 – July 2020)

Cognitive Performance Labs / Ako Maps (www.akomaps.com)

Research, Data, Strategy and Business Intelligence

- Research and reporting of business intelligence information (e.g. market and competitor analyses, pricing analysis, Google Analytics).
- Implementation and analysis of product trials and testing.

Product Management and Customer Experience

- My team and I invented a digital multimedia learning system, which went on to be patented.
- Production of educational courses for corporates, universities and schools.
- Primary liaison with UX (User Experience) contractor. Conducted user interviews and surveys, then prioritised feature requests for the technical team (800+ tickets logged in Jira).

Communication and Client Liaison

- Demonstrated software to clients, including in workshops and presenting to Government ministers, educators, non-profits, and corporate customers.
- Primary liaison with PR contractor; produced marketing / copywriting content.

HR and Operations

- Manager of 4 full-time employees (studio production facility), improved workflows and communicated activities to the CEO.
- Responsible for evaluating CVs, conducting interviews, hiring studio employees, coaching, and performance management.

Apr 2017 – Junior Data Analyst (July 2018 – November 2018)

Nov 2018 **Data Support (April 2017 – June 2018)**

COMET Auckland (Auckland Council-Controlled Organisation)

- Sourced, evaluated and interpreted secondary data sources to report on social indicators and outcomes in the Auckland region.
- Collaborated with stakeholders and presented data to local communities.

Jan 2017 – Data Collection Consultant (Volunteer)

Mar 2017 Helensville Community Recycling Centre

- Created Excel workbooks integrated with point-of-sales system Vend to collect logistical and sales data.
- Created automations of descriptive statistics for reports to Auckland Council.

Education and Qualifications

2022 Web Development Level 6

Enspiral Dev Academy – see *Experience* section.

2018 Bachelor of Science (Hons) in Psychology, awarded with First-Class Honours University of Auckland

- Designing experiments, statistical analysis of data in Excel and IBM SPSS.
- Understanding of neuroscience concepts, including collection and analysis of electroencephalography (EEG) data.

2015 - Bachelor of Arts in Psychology, awarded with Dean's Prize

2017 Auckland University of Technology

• Quantitative research (parametric and nonparametric tests, data presentation).

2010 - Other Academic Qualifications and Awards

2014 Kaipara College

- NCEA Level 1, 2 and 3 with Excellence endorsements.
- Dux of Kaipara College.